<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-08-16T19:43:03+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">James Timothy Meech</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Warp</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/08/16/Warp-firmware.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Warp" /><published>2019-08-16T14:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-16T14:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/08/16/Warp-firmware</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/08/16/Warp-firmware.html">&lt;p&gt;I am currently one of the maintainers of the Warp-firmware. Warp is “a hardware platform to support research in approximate computing, sensor energy optimization, and energy-scavenged
systems. Warp incorporates 11 state-of-the-art sensor integrated
circuits, computation, and an energy-scavenged power supply, all
within a miniature system that is just 3.6 cm×3.3 cm×0.5 cm. Warp’s
sensor integrated circuits together contain a total of 21 sensors with
a range of precisions and accuracies for measuring eight sensing
modalities of acceleration, angular rate, magnetic flux density (compass heading), humidity, atmospheric pressure (elevation), infrared
radiation, ambient temperature, and color. Warp uses a combination
of analog circuits and digital control to facilitate further tradeoffs between sensor and communication accuracy, energy efficiency, and
performance.” According to this &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1804.09241&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; authored by Dr Phillip Stanley-Marbell and Professor Martin Rinard.
Avaliable: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/physical-computation/Warp-firmware&quot;&gt;Warp-firmware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I am currently one of the maintainers of the Warp-firmware. Warp is “a hardware platform to support research in approximate computing, sensor energy optimization, and energy-scavenged systems. Warp incorporates 11 state-of-the-art sensor integrated circuits, computation, and an energy-scavenged power supply, all within a miniature system that is just 3.6 cm×3.3 cm×0.5 cm. Warp’s sensor integrated circuits together contain a total of 21 sensors with a range of precisions and accuracies for measuring eight sensing modalities of acceleration, angular rate, magnetic flux density (compass heading), humidity, atmospheric pressure (elevation), infrared radiation, ambient temperature, and color. Warp uses a combination of analog circuits and digital control to facilitate further tradeoffs between sensor and communication accuracy, energy efficiency, and performance.” According to this article authored by Dr Phillip Stanley-Marbell and Professor Martin Rinard. Avaliable: Warp-firmware</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Solicamb</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/08/16/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Solicamb" /><published>2019-08-16T13:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-16T13:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/08/16/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/08/16/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;SoliCamb is a student-led initiative from the University of Cambridge. I am the chief hardware engineer on this project. In partnership with the Centre for Global Equality, we aim to develop a low cost, durable and easy to use sensing platform to measure soil nutrients and moisture content. Soil health monitoring is essential for the wellbeing of local ecosystems and, on a larger scale, indicative of global warming status. Through engaging citizen scientists in Cambridgeshire (UK) and overseas in Umzimvubu (South Africa), as well as providing access to analysed soil data, this initiative aims to empower and engage the public with global issues relating to environmental sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avaliable: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.solicamb.co.uk/&quot;&gt;SoliCamb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">SoliCamb is a student-led initiative from the University of Cambridge. I am the chief hardware engineer on this project. In partnership with the Centre for Global Equality, we aim to develop a low cost, durable and easy to use sensing platform to measure soil nutrients and moisture content. Soil health monitoring is essential for the wellbeing of local ecosystems and, on a larger scale, indicative of global warming status. Through engaging citizen scientists in Cambridgeshire (UK) and overseas in Umzimvubu (South Africa), as well as providing access to analysed soil data, this initiative aims to empower and engage the public with global issues relating to environmental sustainability.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Star Type Wireless Sensor Network for Future Distributed Structural Health Monitoring Applications</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/08/16/Star-Type-Wireless-Sensor-Network-for-Future-Distributed-Structural-Health-Monitoring-Applications.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Star Type Wireless Sensor Network for Future Distributed Structural Health Monitoring Applications" /><published>2019-08-16T12:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-08-16T12:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/08/16/Star-Type-Wireless-Sensor-Network-for-Future-Distributed-Structural-Health-Monitoring-Applications</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2019/08/16/Star-Type-Wireless-Sensor-Network-for-Future-Distributed-Structural-Health-Monitoring-Applications.html">&lt;p&gt;This article describes a star type wireless sensor network based on nine-axis micro-electromechanical inertial motion sensors with the potential to include up to 254 sensor nodes is presented, and an investigation into the mechanical and structural effects of bell ringing on bell towers is presented as a possible application. This low-power and low-cost system facilitates the continual monitoring of mechanical forces exerted by swinging bells on their support and thus helps avoid structural degradation and damage. Each sensor measures bell rotation, and a novel method utilising only the instantaneous rotational angle is implemented to calculate the force caused by bell ringing. In addition, a commonly used, however, previously experimentally unconfirmed assumption that allows great simplification of force calculations was also proven to be valid by correlating predicted theoretical values with measurement data. Forces produced by ringing a 1425 kg bell in Durham Cathedral were characterised and found to agree with literature. The sensor network will form the basis of a toolkit that provides a scalable turnkey method to determine the exact mechanisms that cause excessive vibration in mechanical and architectural structures, and has the potential to find further applications in low-frequency distributed structural health monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avaliable: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mdpi.com/2411-5134/4/1/6&quot;&gt;Star Type Wireless Sensor Network for Future Distributed Structural Health Monitoring Applications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This article describes a star type wireless sensor network based on nine-axis micro-electromechanical inertial motion sensors with the potential to include up to 254 sensor nodes is presented, and an investigation into the mechanical and structural effects of bell ringing on bell towers is presented as a possible application. This low-power and low-cost system facilitates the continual monitoring of mechanical forces exerted by swinging bells on their support and thus helps avoid structural degradation and damage. Each sensor measures bell rotation, and a novel method utilising only the instantaneous rotational angle is implemented to calculate the force caused by bell ringing. In addition, a commonly used, however, previously experimentally unconfirmed assumption that allows great simplification of force calculations was also proven to be valid by correlating predicted theoretical values with measurement data. Forces produced by ringing a 1425 kg bell in Durham Cathedral were characterised and found to agree with literature. The sensor network will form the basis of a toolkit that provides a scalable turnkey method to determine the exact mechanisms that cause excessive vibration in mechanical and architectural structures, and has the potential to find further applications in low-frequency distributed structural health monitoring.</summary></entry></feed>